podclass.com 2010-11-20

# Privacy Policy

**_Podclass Privacy Policy_**

The privacy practices of this Privacy Policy apply to our services available under the domain and sub-domains of www.podclass.com and domains and subdomains that may be utilizing the services or modules of podclass.com. Please note that this Privacy Policy applies only to sites maintained by podclass.com and not to websites maintained by other companies or organizations to which we link. In addition, this Policy applies only to information collected by Podclass online, not offline. By visiting our websites you agree to be bound by the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree please do not use or access our services.

Podclass.com is an online service that allows you to offer and/or participate in online courses and virtual lectures along with creating your own distinctive personal profile. Podclass provides you with the ability to search for courses as well as individuals that share your common interests and experiences. Podclass also provides a forum for you to network with other users and your instructors through message boards, chat rooms, and blogs. To improve and develop your experience with Podclass.com we request and display some of your personal information to other users which allows you and other users to identify each other and expand each other's network of connections. You are permitted to change your profile at any time and you are permitted to alter and control how others may view your personal information and how Podclass communicates with you.

**_Information Collection and Use_**

Podclass collects personal information submitted by you such as name and email address to authenticate users and send notifications to those users regarding Podclass and any online courses to which the user may subscribe. In addition, in order to assist users in finding and communicating with others Podclass collects additional information such as personal interests, gender, age, education and occupation. Profile information such as member photographs, first names and interests are displayed to facilitate interaction among the users of Podclass. Users' full names are never released to any users or third parties. You may modify or remove any of your personal information at any time by logging your account and accessing "My account."

When you register as a user on Podclass.com (or update/change your user profile) Podclass collects personally identifiable information about you. Podclass utilizes this personally identifiable information to provide you with content that you may request, send emails to you regarding questions about Podclass.com and support, and to inform you of significant changes to this Privacy Policy.

Podclass gathers certain non-personally-identifiable information automatically and stores it in log files. This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data. Podclass uses this information, which does not identify you individually, to analyze trends, to administer the site, to track users' movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. This information, however, when combined together, can be used to identify the originating computer. This information may be provided to third parties to improve Podclass.com and provide additional services and advertisements to users.

Except as otherwise expressly included in this Privacy Policy, this document addresses only the use and disclosure of information we collect from you. If you disclose your information to others, whether they are bidders, buyers or sellers on our sites or other sites throughout the internet, different rules may apply to their use or disclosure of the information you disclose to them. Podclass does not control the privacy policies of third parties, and you are subject to the privacy policies of those third parties where applicable. We encourage you to ask questions before you disclose your personal information to others.

**_Cookies_**

Podclass collects non-personal information through the use of [cookies](http://www.webmd.com/policies/about-privacy-policy#cookie%23cookie). When you use your computer to access Podclass.com your computer will be assigned a different cookie by Podclass.com. Assigning your computer a cookie allows Podclass to monitor how many people visit Podclass.com and the links to third parties' sites, if you open email sent to you and what portions of Podclass.com you visit. We also use cookies to facilitate the log-in process and to provide navigation assistance for Podclass.com.

You are able to set your browser to reject cookies. You are able to so (with most browsers) by selecting "Help" in your browser's toolbar and using the pull-down menu to select a feature which will block cookies. If you elect to reject cookies, certain functions of Podclass.com may not operate properly or in an optimal fashion, however you do not have to accept Podclass cookies to use Podclass.com. Podclass does not match non-personal information received from cookies to personally identifiable information without your permission and Podclass does not use cookies to collect or store personal information about you.

**_Tell-a-friend Communications to Non-members_**

Upon completion of a course sign-up, you can invite friends to join Podclass and the course you have enrolled in by sending invitation emails. Podclass stores the email addresses that you provide so that the invitees may be added to your friend's list and also to send reminders of the invitations. Podclass does not sell the email addresses that you may provide or send any communications other than the course invitations and subsequent invitation reminders. Individuals who receive invitation emails from Podclass may contact Podclass to request no additional communications.

You may prevent Podclass email invitations and other Podclass messages from being sent to any email address you control by contacting Podclass at remove@podclass.com [The email must come from the account you wish to block.]

**_Third Party Advertising_**

Advertisements that appear on Podclass.com may be delivered to you by Podclass or one of our web advertising associates. Our web advertising associates may set cookies that allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time it sends you an online advertisement. This information allows an ad network to deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you for through the use of cookies, ad servers may compile information about where you, or others who are using your computer, saw their advertisements and determine which ads are clicked on. This privacy statement covers the use of cookies by Podclass.com and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.

**_Third Party Links_**

Podclass.com may contain links to third party sites. Podclass is not responsible for the privacy policies and/or practices on other sites. When you are transferred to another site through a third party link you should read the privacy policy stated on that site, as this Privacy Policy only governs information collected on Podclass.com.

**_Sharing and Disclosure of Information_**

Except as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy, Podclass will not disclose personal information to any third party unless Podclass believes that disclosure is necessary: (i) to conform to legal requirements or to respond to a subpoena, search warrant or other legal process, whether or not a response is required by applicable law; (ii) to protect the safety of members of the public and users of the service; or (iii) to enforce the Podclass [Terms of Use](http://www.podclass.com/podclass/terms) or to protect its rights. Podclass reserves the right to transfer personal information to a successor in interest that acquires rights to that information as a result of the sale of all or substantially all of its assets to that successor in interest.

**_Spam_**

Spam is not permitted. You are not licensed to add other users, even a user who has purchased a course or lecture from you, to your mailing list (email or physical mail) without their express consent. You may not use our communication tools to send spam or otherwise send content that would violate our [Terms of Use](http://www.podclass.com/podclass/terms).

**_Use of Podclass.com by Children under the age of 13_**

Podclass believes that protecting the privacy of children is important. Although the content on Podclass.com may be used by a parent or guardian of a child under the age of thirteen to benefit such a child, neither Podclass nor any of its services are designed or intended to attract children under the age of 13. Although Podclass does not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from a person Podclass actually knows is under the age of 13, Podclass does allow a child's parent or guardian, to establish a user profile on behalf of the child. The parent or guardian is solely responsible for providing supervision of the child's use of Podclass.com and a parent or guardian who registers a child shall assume full responsibility for ensuring that the registration information is kept secure and that the information submitted is accurate and complete. Any such parent or guardian also assumes full responsibility for the interpretation and use of any information or suggestions provided through Podclass.com for the minor.

**_Message Boards, Chat Rooms, Blogs and Public Forums_**

Please be aware that whenever you voluntarily post public information to message boards, chat rooms, blogs or any other public forum the information that you post can be accessed by the public and can in turn be used by those people to send you unsolicited communications.

**_Email Choice/Opt-out_**

If you no longer desire to receive updates or notifications you may opt out of such updates and notifications by logging your account and accessing "My account" and changing your email preferences.

**_Security_**

Podclass takes precautionary measures to insure that your information is kept private. Your account is secured by a member-created password. Podclass uses reasonable measures to protect your information that is stored within our database and Podclass restricts access to your information to only those employees of Podclass who need access to such information to perform their job functions, such as our technical staff and customer service personnel. Unauthorized entry or use, hardware or software failure, and other factors may compromise the security of your information at any time, therefore we cannot guarantee the security of your information.

**_Changes in Our Privacy Policy_**

From time to time Podclass may make changes to this Privacy Policy. If Podclass makes changes, Podclass will post them on the site to make you aware of what the changes are so you will always be aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and when we may disclose it. You are bound by any minor changes to the policy when you use the site after those changes have been posted. If, however, Podclass is going to use your personally identifiable information in a manner materially different from that stated at the time of collection we will notify you by posting a notice on Podclass.com for thirty (30) days.

**_Contacting Podclass_**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of Podclass, or your dealings with Podclass.com, please contact us at privacy@podclass.com.
